<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Chronic Disease General Practice Phns on HEALTHSquare</title>
    <link>/tags/chronic-disease-general-practice-phns/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Chronic Disease General Practice Phns on HEALTHSquare</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2016 22:44:05 +1000</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="/tags/chronic-disease-general-practice-phns/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    <item>
      <title>Briefing: Health Care Homes</title>
      <link>/news/20160903/brief-health-care-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2016 22:44:05 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/20160903/brief-health-care-home/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;This new way of funding care for patients with chronic and complex conditions is one of the biggest health system reforms since the introduction of Medicare 30 years ago.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Eligible patients in up to seven Primary Health Network regions will voluntarily enrol with a participating medical practice known as their Health Care Home. This practice will provide a patient with a home base for the ongoing coordination, management and support of their conditions. Patients enrolled in a Health Care Home will nominate a preferred clinician, usually a GP. A tailored care plan will be developed in partnership with the patient.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;table&gt;
&lt;thead&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;th&gt;State&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;th&gt;Home Care Home Stage 1 - July 2017&lt;/th&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/thead&gt;

&lt;tbody&gt;
&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;ACT&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;No&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;NSW&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Hunter New England and Central CoastWestern Sydney Nepean Blue Mountains&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;NT&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Qld&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Brisbane North&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;SA&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Adelaide Country SA&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Tas&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Yes&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Vic&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;South Eastern Melbourne&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;

&lt;tr&gt;
&lt;td&gt;WA&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;td&gt;Perth North&lt;/td&gt;
&lt;/tr&gt;
&lt;/tbody&gt;
&lt;/table&gt;

&lt;p&gt;nd be limited to Medicare-eligible patients with two or more complex or chronic conditions. The aim of a successful Health Care Home model is to keep patients healthy at home and out of hospital by providinghttps://drive.google.com/open?id=0B5mPh9C6qLOmQjBHUl9fU08zVHc&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;continuity of care, coordinated services and a team approach based on the needs of the patient.&lt;br /&gt;
How many&lt;br /&gt;
Health Care Homes will include general practices and Aboriginal Medical Services. Health Care Homes will assess and enrol patients according to their level of risk, deliver coordinated clinical care that better engages the broader health care team, enhance patient engagement, and provide de-identified data.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;The payment system for patients enrolled in Health Care Homes will change, with the introduction of quarterly bundled payments to general practices. Fee-for-service payments will remain for routine non-chronic disease-related care. The bundled payment will provide clinicians with flexibility to accommodate regional differences and individual patient needs.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;A national rollout of Health Care Homes will be informed by the results of a rigorous evaluation of the first stage of implementation and consideration by Government.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Chronic disease places an enormous burden on the health system. The rising incidence of chronic disease is a significant driver of Australia’s rising health costs.&lt;br /&gt;
A trial of up to 200 Health Care Homes will offer services to up to 65,000 people with chronic and complex conditions.&lt;br /&gt;
Health Care Homes will provide continuity of care, coordinated services and a team-based approach to care according to the needs and wishes of the patient.&lt;br /&gt;
Health care practitioners will benefit from a payment system that allows them the flexibility to deliver health care in the most effective way for individual patients. Payments will be made quarterly rather than on a fee per service basis.&lt;br /&gt;
Investing in prevention and management of chronic disease keeps people healthier and out of hospital, easing the strain on the hospital system, and increasing efficiency across the wider health system.&lt;br /&gt;
How much will this cost?&lt;br /&gt;
This measure will cost $21.3 million from 2015–16 to 2018–19.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Health care homes to be rolled out from -changed in health care home trial</title>
      <link>/news/20160903/health-care-home/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Sep 2016 22:44:05 +1000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>/news/20160903/health-care-home/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;**The Federal Government&amp;rsquo;s new health care home model for people living with chronic conditions will be rolled out across 10 regions from 2017.&lt;br /&gt;
South Eastern Melbourne&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;&amp;laquo;The Health Care Homes model has to work for rural and remote communities. This has to work equally as well&lt;br /&gt;
for the patient living in Thargomindah as it does for the patient living in inner-city Sydney.&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;laquo;The model must be flexible enough to meet the unique needs of small rural and remote communities. And it&lt;br /&gt;
must reflect the fact that the provision of healthcare works differently in rural and remote areas than it does in&lt;br /&gt;
urban settings.&lt;br /&gt;
&amp;laquo;A Health Care Homes approach to chronic care is something that RDAA has been calling for and strongly&lt;br /&gt;
supports, but it must improve access to care for rural and remote Australians&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>